natali vlatko

dolziger straße 28 • 10247 berlin, germany • CELL (+49) 152 2777 8666 • E-MAIL natalivlatko@gmail.com •

PROFILE

Writing, editing, communications, strategy. Strong background in research and analysis, with close attention to detail. Well organised, efficient, and can operate effectively when working individually or within a team. Experience in companies with a global reach, spanning several countries (Australia, Singapore, Germany).

Proficient in various open source versions of proprietary software including CMS, chat clients, office suites, and browsers.

EXPERIENCE

Head of Tech Communications (Wayfair) BERLIN, GERMANY - NOV 2017 - PRESENT

- Help develop and coordinate a tech communications strategy and additional services to grow Wayfair's global technology brand, showcasing its technical prowess and initiatives.
- Create and contribute to strategic communication plans that drive broader visibility via various social media and blogging channels, plus internal channels.
- Prepare communications materials in partnership with Public Relations for tech media and stakeholders including articles, presentations, speeches, and other digital support materials.
- Close monitoring, documenting, and reporting of social media and blog activity, including analytical statistics and data.
- Review speaking and event sponsorship opportunities for the Engineering department globally.
- Write and edit opinion pieces, thought leadership articles, and internal communications on behalf of Wayfair's Engineering leadership.
- Curate and coordinate Wayfair's Open Source Software strategy, whilst working with Engineering teams to produce accurate documentation for projects and craft marketing plans for their release.
- Work with Tech Talent Development teams to plan, organize, and execute hackathons for the wider Engineering population at Wayfair, extending it's scope for Data Science and Product groups.
- Facilitate the creation and maintenance of tech resources such as Wayfair's Tech Radar, Tech Blog, and Newsletter content, working closely with Talent Acquisition for utilisation in recruiting.

Corporate Communications Manager - Tech, Zalando SE BERLIN, GERMANY - MAR 2016 - OCT 2017

Journalist/Editor, Software & Support Media (JAXenter.com) BERLIN, GERMANY - JAN 2015 - JAN 2016

Admissions/Student Services Manager, Nexus International School SINGAPORE, SINGAPORE - 2013 - MAY 2014

Customer Service Manager, APACSALE Group SINGAPORE, SINGAPORE - 2013

Client Services Manager, State Library of New South Wales SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA - 2011 - JAN 2013

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Ancient History University of Macquarie, NSW - 2012

Bachelor of Arts, History, Politics, Philosophy University of Western Sydney, NSW - 2009